本期视频由Squarespace赞助
This episode of Primal Space is supported by Squarespace.
前往squarespace.com/primalspace获取免费试用与首单九折的优惠
Get a free trial plus 10% off your first purchase by visiting squarespace.com/primalspace.
1989年 在太空飞行了12年的旅行者二号成为了首次飞越海王星的探测器
In 1989, 12 years after leaving Earth, Voyager 2 became the first spacecraft to fly past the mysterious planet of Neptune.
在当时 人们对这个星球知之甚少
At this point, very little was known about the planet,
科学家们只预测到了它的存在 却还未实际观测过
and scientists had only predicted its existence without actually observing it.
当旅行者号飞跃的时候 它拍摄了海王星首批照片
As it flew by, Voyager took the very first images of Neptune,
向人类展示了一个中央带有巨大深色斑点的光滑蓝色圆球
showing a smooth blue ball with a giant dark spot right in the center.
这个深色斑点之后发现是一场大风暴
This dark spot turned out to be a gigantic storm.
5年后 海王星再次被哈勃太空望远镜观测到
5 years later, Neptune was observed again, this time by the Hubble Space telescope.
当科学家们收到画面时 他们惊讶地发现深色斑点竟然完全消失了
When scientists received the images, they were stunned to see that the dark spot had completely disappeared.
他们猜测海王星的大风暴和木星的大红斑类似
They assumed that Neptune's enormous storm must be similar to Jupiter's Red Spot,
持续了大约350年
which has been around for at least 350 years.
本期视频 我们将了解这些巨大的风暴是如何形成的
In this video, we're going to look at how these enormous storms form.
我们还将了解木星的大红斑 以及它为什么可能在我们有生之年消失
We're also going to look at Jupiter's Great Red Spot and why it might disappear in our lifetime.
有记载的地球上最大的风暴是1994年的飓风“约翰”
The longest storm ever recorded on Earth was Hurricane John in 1994.
它持续31天 路径总长超过13000公里 横跨太平洋
It lasted 31 days and travelled over 13,000 kilometres as it wandered across the Pacific Ocean.
尽管它是地球上非常大的风暴
Although this is a monumental storm by Earth standards,
但和海王星 木星上持续时间几个月几年甚至几世纪的风暴相比还是图样
it's nothing compared to the storms on Neptune and Jupiter, which can last for months, years, or even centuries.
在地球上 飓风起源于海上蒸发的暖湿水汽
On Earth, the power of a hurricane comes from warm vapour evaporating from the sea.
形成密集的云后 会向空气中释放热量
This forms dense clouds which release heat into the air.
在特定条件下 这会产生一个低压区域
In the right conditions, this creates an area of low pressure
暖空气上升 冷空气被吸入底部
with warm air rising and cooler air being sucked in at the bottom.
而地球在赤道附近的自转线速度更大
Since the Earth spins at a higher velocity closer to the equator,
流向低压区的风开始偏转 让飓风产生旋转
winds travelling towards the area of low pressure begin to curve which causes the hurricane to spin.
飓风通常会在遇到陆地后开始消散
A hurricane will usually start to dissipate once it reaches land,
因为没有暖湿水汽的供给 也就无法让它继续旋转
where it no longer receives the warm vapour it needs to keep the cycle going.
与地球上的典型的气旋不同 木星的大红斑是反气旋
Unlike typical cyclones on Earth, the Great Red Spot on Jupiter is an anticyclone
它产生于高压区
which forms around an area of high pressure.
大红斑的动力来源于两侧的气流
The red spot is powered by two jet streams on either side
让大红斑持续旋转 又让它无法沿着星球到处移动
which give the storm a constant spin but stop it from moving across the planet.
地球上的风暴动力来自于太阳给地球的热量
While a storm on Earth is powered by the heat from the sun,
木星上的风暴动力则来自于它自身高达27700摄氏度的金属内核
a storm on Jupiter is powered by the heat from its metallic core, which could be as hot as 50,000 degrees.
上升的热流和快速移动的云
The combination of rising heat and fast moving clouds
让大红斑的边缘风速可以高达每小时680公里
are what push the Great Red Spot around with speeds of up to 680 km/h.
且木星是气态行星 它没有所谓的海洋或者陆地这种“屏障”
Since Jupiter is a gas giant, it doesn't have the contrast of ocean and land to act as a barrier.
海王星的风暴则起因于类似的 大气深处的高压区
The storms on Neptune form around a similar region of high pressure, deep in the atmosphere.
深色斑点形成前通常能在高压区见到白色的甲烷云
White clouds of methane are commonly seen in regions of high pressure
just before a dark spot forms.
当海王星上的风暴逐渐成长为完全体
Once a storm on Neptune has grown to its full size,
边缘风速可以达到每小时2100公里 是全太阳系最大的风
the winds at the edge of the storm can be travelling up to 2,100km/h, the fastest in our solar system.
与木星大红斑不同的是 海王星上的风暴可以满星球到处跑
Unlike Jupiter's Red Spot, the storms on Neptune get pushed around the planet
并会被侧风吹散分解
where they get shredded by powerful crosswinds.
因此 海王星上各地的风暴通常持续几个月到几年不等
Because of this, storms on Neptune typically last anywhere from a few months to a few years.
因为地球上观测木星更容易 人类观测大红斑的历史
Since Jupiter is much easier to see from Earth, our observations of the red spot go back
也能追溯到1665年天文学家乔凡尼·多美尼科·卡西尼对其的首次观测
to 1665 when Astronomer Gian Domenico Cassini first discovered the giant storm.
从那以后 人类能够一直观测它 并见证它的变化
Since then, we have been able to observe the red spot and watch it evolve over time.
然而 这些观测发现这场象征木星标志的风暴可能快要结束了
However, these observations have shown that the end may be near for this iconic storm.
在19世纪的观测中 大红斑长40000公里 高14000公里
When it was observed in the 19th century, the Great Red Spot was 40,000km long and 14,000km tall.
当时 它能装下两到三个地球
At that point, it could have swallowed 2 or 3 earths whole.
但旅行者一号在70年代末飞越的时候 大红斑却只有几乎一半大小
But by the time Voyager 1 flew past in the late 70s, it was almost half the size.
哈勃最近的观测发现大红斑在以每年1000公里的速度缩小
Recent observations by the Hubble telescope show that the storm is currently shrinking at about 1000km per year,
这意味着它可能会在2030年彻底消失
meaning it could completely disappear by the 2030's.
除了在缩小 大红斑主体看上去还在被分解成更小的气流 颜色也在变深
As well as losing size, the main red spot seems to be breaking off into smaller streams and darkening in color.
科学家们认为风暴正在接近木星的高层大气
Scientists believe that since the storm is reaching higher into the atmosphere,
大红斑的顶部会受到更多紫外线的照射 让其中的化学物质颜色变深
the top of the red spot is exposed to more UV light which darkens the color of the chemicals.
但这和地球上的天气预报一样 这些巨大风暴背后还有很多人类未解之谜
But, like predicting the weather here on Earth, there is still so much that we don't know about these gigantic storms.
当人类首次发现海王星的深色斑点时
When Neptune's Dark Spot was first discovered,
科学家们以为它和木星的大红斑一样存在了几个世纪
scientists thought that it had been around for centuries just like Jupiter's storm.
大红斑的温度也比我们预料的要高
The Great Red Spot is also far hotter than we initially imagined,
它上部的大气温度超过1300度
with parts of it's upper atmosphere exceeding 1300 degrees.
即使我们观测的技术在不断进步
Even with the increases in our observational technology,
这些巨大 未知的星球仍有无数知识等待我们去探寻
there is still so much knowledge trapped inside the boundaries of these giant, mysterious planets, waiting to be discovered.
虽然我们可能将要失去太阳系最有象征意义的符号
So although we might be losing one of the most iconic features of our solar system,
但我们对它有限的观测却能让我们更好的理解太阳系内的自然法则
the observations we make of it will give us a better understanding of how nature operates throughout our solar system.
在Squarespace上创建网站简直太容易了
Creating a website for your business with Squarespace is incredibly easy.
如果你是搞艺术或者搞摄影的
If you are an artist or a photographer,
有一个专门的网站供人们浏览 购买作品是很有必要的
having an all-in-one place where people can admire and purchase your work is essential.
从无数设计好的模板里选择 快速搭建一个专业网站来展示你的作品
Choose from a number of pre-designed templates to quickly create a professional website that showcases your work.
有了Squarespace 你可以开网店 卖你的作品 开创自己的产业
With Squarespace, you can set up an online store, where you can sell your work and start growing your own business.
Squarespace还会提供分析功能 比如网页浏览量 访问来源 销量等等
Squarespace also provides you with full access to analytics like: page views, traffic sources, sales and more.
除了配置第三方域名 客户还可以直接在Squarespace上购买域名
In addition to configuring third party domains, customers can purchase domains directly from Squarespace.
如果想建立自己的网站 那就快去squarespace.com获取免费试用吧
Head to squarespace.com for a free trial and when you're ready to launch your website,
前往squarespace.com/primalspace并使用优惠码"primalspace"可以首单九折
go to squarespace.com/primalspace and add the code Primal Space to save 10% off your first website or domain.
感谢观看 我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.